In short, this course is broken into two parts.
The first part is about making decisions--about how computation can give rise to
behavior. We're going to think about about how do search and planning, how to do constraint satisfaction,
and how to think about the
presence of adversaries and uncertainty.
The second part of this course is about
reasoning when there's uncertainty,
and about learning. We're gonna think
about representing knowledge, uncertain
knowledge with Bayes nets, we're going to talk about decision theory and machine learning.
This is the two sides of AI that I
talked about. When you make a good
decision it's partly because of memory,
you've learned from the past,
and it's partly because of prediction,
you have a model of the consequences of your actions.
We're going to learn how to blend these two things
together to give rise to sophisticated
and intelligent behaviors.
Throughout all of this,
we're gonna have applications like
natural language and vision and robotics,
and games.
So,
thank you for attending this first lecture of CS 188,
and we will see you next lecture.